This is one of the craziest thought
experiments in all of physics. Say
you're at the beach when all of a sudden
you see your friend struggling out in
the water. You want to go help him as
quickly as possible, so which path
should you take to get there? Well, the
shortest path is a straight line, so you
could head directly towards him. But you
can run faster than you can swim, and
this path requires more swimming. So
alternatively, you could run down the
beach to minimize the distance through
the water. But now the total distance is
longer than it needs to be. So the
optimal path, it turns out, is somewhere
in between. To be precise, it depends on
the speed at which you can run and swim.
Now, you might recognize this
mathematical relationship because it is
the exact same law that governs light
passing from one medium to another. So
light also takes the fastest path from
point A to point B. But that raises the
question. See, you made a choice on how
to go as fast as possible, but how does
light know which path to take? Now, you
might say there's nothing strange about
this. Light just sets out in some
direction, it hits an interface, and
then it changes [music] direction. But
that is not what's happening. Instead,
light, and in fact all particles,
electrons, basketballs, [music] even
you, explore all possible paths all at
once. And the final path we see is in
some ways one of the greatest illusions
there is.